<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>dry ice blasting services</title>
    <link href="https://automaniacmrk.github.io/DryIceBlastingServices/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://automaniacmrk.github.io/DryIceBlastingServices" />
    <updated>2022-07-03T20:03:59-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Cleaner</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://automaniacmrk.github.io/DryIceBlastingServices</id>

    <entry>
        <title>How Does Dry Ice Blasting Work?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Cleaner</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://automaniacmrk.github.io/DryIceBlastingServices/how-does-dry-ice-blasting-work.html"/>
        <id>https://automaniacmrk.github.io/DryIceBlastingServices/how-does-dry-ice-blasting-work.html</id>

        <updated>2022-06-27T07:27:33-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    How Does Dry Ice Blasting Work? Dry ice blasting is a non-destructive cleaning process that uses solid carbon dioxide to dislodge residue while leaving the surface intact. Similar in concept to pressure washing, dry ice blasting uses compressed air to project media toward a surface&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h2>How Does Dry Ice Blasting Work?</h2>
<p>Dry ice blasting is a non-destructive cleaning process that uses solid carbon dioxide to dislodge residue while leaving the surface intact. Similar in concept to pressure washing, dry ice blasting uses compressed air to project media toward a surface at a high velocity. In this case, the media are carbon dioxide particles, which form solid pellets when cooled to -109.3 degrees Fahrenheit. Three immediate results can be obtained by blasting frozen carbon dioxide on a surface:</p>
<ul>
<li>The surface's contents freeze and fracture due to thermal shock before the pellets even make contact.</li>
<li>High-speed collisions between pellets and brittle contaminants break down unwanted residue into smaller pieces.</li>
<li>Exposure to room temperature air causes the dry ice to rapidly vaporize, resulting in an explosive effect that dislodges more debris.</li>
</ul>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://callawayindustrial.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/dry-ice-blasting-services.jpg" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Dry Ice Blasting Services" data-cke-saved-src=" https://callawayindustrial.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/dry-ice-blasting-services.jpg"></p>
<h2>How to Use Abrasive Blazing</h2>
<ul>
<li>Abrasive blasting offers flexibility because of the variety of media available. The media chosen can be customized to fit the surface material and the contaminant being removed. When the surrounding surface is free from electrical and mechanical components, such as concrete silos, brick walls, or other steel structures, abrasive blasting can be used. The surface can also be profiled to allow for future applications or to shape the surface. Abrasive blasting requires cleanup of media and will not work in indoor areas that can't handle dust and excess mess.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Abrasive blasting offers flexibility because of the variety of media available. You can customize the media to match the material or the removal of the contaminant.</li>
<li>Abrasive blasting is ideal when the surface and surrounding area has no electrical or mechanical parts that could be damaged through the media being used, such as a sturdy brick wall, a concrete silo, or steel equipment.</li>
<li>This method is also used when the surface needs to be profiled for another application or shaping of the surface needs to happen.</li>
<li>Abrasive blasting will require cleanup and removal of the media, so for indoor spaces that cannot handle excessive mess and dust, abrasive blasting may not be ideal.</li>
</ul>
<h2>What is Dry Ice used in Cleaning?</h2>
<p>Dry ice blasting and cleaning uses compressed air to push CO2 pellets from a tube using a narrow tip that is aimed at the surface. Although it looks much like pressure washing or sand blasting, the big difference is that dry ice is - dry. Because the CO2 is cold (109 degrees below zero), dirt molecules shrink and are released from the surface. The ice pellets become gas when they hit the surface. This creates a molecular blast that removes dirt, grease, and paint from the surface without significantly cooling it.</p>
<ul>
<li>The only thing left to do is sweep up the residue of paint, ink, resins, asphalt, grime, adhesives or whatever has been removed from surfaces. No waste water. No chemical drainage. No sand or plastic beads scattered around. The CO2 solid pellets dissipate into the air and are absorbed by the atmosphere.</li>
<li>There is no dust or detritus from dry ice blasting that can be trapped in or foul up either the machinery being cleaned or nearby equipment.</li>
<li>The pellets are non-toxic; pose no workplace hazard to people or equipment, and meet EPA, USDA and FDA guidelines.</li>
</ul>
<p>With Ice Cleaning, you no longer have to take apart industrial equipment, move it to a cleaning area, and then move it back to the manufacturing floor to be reassembled. This allows you to clean it in situ, which greatly reduces downtime. The dry ice blasting nozzle is agile for reaching most exposed areas. You can clean the entire thing by doing some in-place disassembly if necessary.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Industries and Applications of Dry Ice Blasting</title>
        <author>
            <name>Cleaner</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://automaniacmrk.github.io/DryIceBlastingServices/industries-and-applications-of-dry-ice-blasting.html"/>
        <id>https://automaniacmrk.github.io/DryIceBlastingServices/industries-and-applications-of-dry-ice-blasting.html</id>

        <updated>2022-06-27T07:25:45-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Dry ice blasting is an effective solution for removing unwanted contaminants and residues from the production process, such as: Oils Adhesives Resins Paints Greases Asphalt tars Biofilms Aerospace. The aerospace sector relies on dry ice blasting to remove mastic from parts; clean turbine blades; remove&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><img loading="lazy" src="http://constructco.com/Removing%20sulfur%20deposits%20prior%20to%20welding.JPG" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Dry Ice Blasting Services" data-cke-saved-src=" http://constructco.com/Removing%20sulfur%20deposits%20prior%20to%20welding.JPG"></p>
<h2>Industries and Applications of Dry Ice Blasting</h2>
<p>Dry ice blasting is an effective solution for removing unwanted contaminants and residues from the production process, such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>Oils</li>
<li>Adhesives</li>
<li>Resins</li>
<li>Paints</li>
<li>Greases</li>
<li>Asphalt tars</li>
<li>Biofilms</li>
<li>Aerospace. The aerospace sector relies on dry ice blasting to remove mastic from parts; clean turbine blades; remove labels from fuselage; and clean hydraulics, electrical components and circuitry, and landing gear.</li>
<li>Automotive. Dry Ice Blazing is excellent for cleaning undercarriages and engine components, as well as wheels and axles and automotive production equipment.</li>
<li>Power plants and electrical equipment. Dry ice blasting is often used to remove oil residue and/or corrosion from power generation equipment, such as turbines and generators. Dry ice blasting is also used in nuclear decontamination and for resin removal in the production of transformers.</li>
<li>Fire remediation. After a fire, dry ice blasting can be used to remove any charring or ash from other usable components.</li>
<li>Foundries and metal production. This process is used by foundries for cleaning molds and pressing equipment, stripping paint and rust, deburring and cleaning welder robots, residue removal and many other purposes.</li>
<li>Mold remediation. Dry ice blasting is a great option for applications that need sanitation.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Here are a few of the benefits to dry ice blasting:</h2>
<ul>
<li>No machine disassembly and reassembly is needed - this means companies won't have much unproductive downtime.</li>
<li>A quicker clean, that's non-abrasive, non-conductive, non-flammable.</li>
<li>There is no secondary waste or cleanup, which saves money on labor and expenses.</li>
<li>Companies that have used other methods of cleaning may find it difficult to reach tight areas with our blasting nozzles.</li>
<li>Environment-friendly - Meets the requirements of USDA, FDA, and EPA.</li>
<li>Safe for employees - no exposure to chemicals or grit media</li>
</ul>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Dry Ice Blasting Compared To Other Methods</title>
        <author>
            <name>Cleaner</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://automaniacmrk.github.io/DryIceBlastingServices/dry-ice-blasting-compared-to-other-methods.html"/>
        <id>https://automaniacmrk.github.io/DryIceBlastingServices/dry-ice-blasting-compared-to-other-methods.html</id>

        <updated>2022-07-03T20:03:59-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Dry Ice Blasting Compared To Other Methods There are many available methods for cleaning industrial equipment. Each method has advantages and drawbacks, and some are comparable to dry ice blasting in some areas while falling short in others. These are the differences between other cleaning&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h2>Dry Ice Blasting Compared To Other Methods</h2>
<p>There are many available methods for cleaning industrial equipment. Each method has advantages and drawbacks, and some are comparable to dry ice blasting in some areas while falling short in others. These are the differences between other cleaning techniques and dry ice blasting.</p>
<ul>
<li>Abrasive blasting. Abrasive blasting can be dangerous and toxic for operators, unlike dry ice blasting. To avoid being exposed to fumes or dust, the operator should wear a mask and a breathing device.</li>
<li>Soda blasting. Abrasive blasting can be used in a variety of ways, including soda blasting.</li>
<li>You can pressure wash. Pressure washing, like dry ice blasting is not abrasive. It does not cause any harm to the environment by emitting or toxic chemicals. In contrast, this method is electrically conductive and require wastewater disposal.</li>
<li>Tools for hand. These tools can be used in an environmentally friendly manner, do not use toxic substances, are non-conductive and don't require special waste management. Hand tools have a lot of disadvantages, including abrasiveness and additional labor requirements.</li>
</ul>
<p>Dry ice blasting offers safety advantages that are not available with other industrial cleaning techniques. These are the most important:</p>
<ul>
<li>Emissions and elimination of toxic chemicals</li>
<li>Reduced waste of cleaning solutions</li>
<li>Prevention of surface degradation from abrasives</li>
</ul>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.eximotek.co.in/images/Dry-ice-blasting_product_image.png" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Dry Ice Blasting Services" data-cke-saved-src=" http://www.eximotek.co.in/images/Dry-ice-blasting_product_image.png"></p>
<h2>The Project Required That The Walls Be Cleaned Down To White Metal</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.aenviro.com/dry-ice-blasting/">Dry ice blasting is a good solution for everything</a> from removing heavy slag to cleaning sensitive semi-conductors. This is a fast and simple process that can be done quickly at a low cost.</p>
<ul>
<li>It's fast: You don't have to do any post-cleanup, because you won’t waste any water.</li>
<li>Uncomplicated: there is no grit or dust left behind even though the technique is as effective as abrasive sandblasting</li>
<li>It is cost-effective: Many machinery can be cleaned online or with little downtime. There are no disposal costs or time losses.</li>
</ul>
<p>Dry ice is a great way to clean any grime-covered surface without damaging it. Unlike sand, bead blasting, or chemicals, dry ice (CO2) pellets will not leave pits or scratches. CO2 is not a hazardous chemical, unlike most industrial cleaning solvents.</p>
<h2>Information</h2>
<p>Advanced Environmental award-winning CryoDetail(r) division is the first and original dry ice blasting facility in North America for automotive restoration and preservation. Over a decade worth of experience has been gained with rare and exotic vehicles. Experts, collectors and judges of concours are all familiar with CryoDetail(r). We are pioneers in this service and look forward to the opportunity to take your vehicle to the next level of perfection.</p>
<p>Any vehicle as well as mechanical components such as engine assemblies, suspensions, transmissions &amp; more can be brought back to factory new condition with CryoDetail(r) while significantly reducing the hundreds of hours in labor usually required for cleaning components. Therefore, producing a significant savings for your vehicle's restoration and/or preservation projects.</p>
<p>CryoDetail (r) is the only EPA-approved method of industrial cleaning. It can save hundreds of hours that were once required to clean parts. Dry ice does not need to be treated with harmful chemicals, and leaves no residues. CryoDetail(r) is the safest and most environmentally friendly treatment for restoring and/or preserving your vehicle.</p>
<p>While some of our clients have had their daily drivers and track cars treated with CryoDetail(r), clients with collector and antique as well as show cars are mostly attracted to this service to maintain or to turn their cars into show car and concours winners. Some of the cars won Concours d'Elegance Awards at Pebble Beach and PCA National Parade as well as Cavallino Classic, Celebration Exotic Festivals, Mandarin By The Bay, Amelia Island, Cavallino Classic and Celebration Exotic Festival to name a few.</p>
<p>We appreciate you visiting our website. Please feel free to look through our cars and watch our videos. Also please do not hesitate to call us directly to bring your vehicle back to it's factory new look.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Dry Ice Cleaning And Blasting In Industrial Applications Services</title>
        <author>
            <name>Cleaner</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://automaniacmrk.github.io/DryIceBlastingServices/dry-ice-cleaning-and-blasting-in-industrial-applications-services.html"/>
        <id>https://automaniacmrk.github.io/DryIceBlastingServices/dry-ice-cleaning-and-blasting-in-industrial-applications-services.html</id>

        <updated>2022-06-27T07:23:49-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Dry Ice Cleaning And Blasting In Industrial Applications Services Electrical parts and generators can be back in service immediately because you don't have to wait for water or chemicals to dry. Dry ice blasting of radioactive deposits is simpler because the contaminated residue requires far&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h1><img loading="lazy" src="https://uscleanblast.com/wp-content/uploads/Attach0-300x225.jpg" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Dry Ice Blasting Services" data-cke-saved-src=" https://uscleanblast.com/wp-content/uploads/Attach0-300x225.jpg"></h1>
<h2>Dry Ice Cleaning And Blasting In Industrial Applications Services</h2>
<p>Electrical parts and generators can be back in service immediately because you don't have to wait for water or chemicals to dry. Dry ice blasting of radioactive deposits is simpler because the contaminated residue requires far smaller storage containers than would contaminated waste water from pressure washing. Dry ice is being used for cleaning in applications around the world including:</p>
<ul>
<li>Inside Heat Exchanger Tubes - Inside Diameter (ID)</li>
<li>Outside Fin Fans Cooler cleaning</li>
<li>Fire Restoration and Cleanup</li>
<li>Smoke Damage Restoration</li>
<li>Presses for printing</li>
<li>Manufacturing equipment cleaning</li>
<li>Piping Cleaning and Maintenance</li>
<li>Storage tanks</li>
<li>Reactor Cleaning</li>
<li>Shell and Tube Heating exchangers</li>
<li>Oil field equipment</li>
<li>Turbines, transformers</li>
<li>Sub-stations for power</li>
<li>Boilers</li>
<li>Molds and Presses</li>
<li>Electric Motors and Circuit Boards</li>
<li>Food Processing Equipment</li>
<li>Generators</li>
<li>Gears</li>
</ul>
<p>Industries and commercial companies are also using dry ice blasting to complete periodic maintenance cleaning projects, because of the ability to avoid or isolate downtime. Increasingly the method is being used in the food industry, for safe cleaning of ovens and packaging lines.</p>
<p>Dry ice has replaced solvents that damage the environment and are a workplace hazard, from acids to caustics. It also removes hazardous waste disposal fees that can be very costly because it does not contain the chemical drainage or the residual chemicals.</p>
<h2>Our Technology</h2>
<p>Dry ice cleaning is non-abrasive, non-conductive, non-toxic, and non-flammable. The ice cleaning process is chemical-free, water-free and doesn't create secondary waste streams. The dry ice blasting machine is incredibly versatile and can be used for a wide range of applications and industries.</p>
<p>The benefits of dry ice blasting</p>
<ul>
<li>Increase efficiency Clean equipment online, while eliminating need for cooldown and disassembly.</li>
<li>Secondary waste is not produced by dry ice blasting.</li>
<li>Non-abrasive Dry Ice is a media that does not cause damage to substrates.</li>
<li>Higher quality parts and less scrap</li>
<li>Operator safe Eliminates need for chemicals and repetitive, manual processes.</li>
<li>It is non-conductive and toxic. Dry Ice is suitable for commercial usage.</li>
</ul>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Dry Ice Blasting Services</title>
        <author>
            <name>Cleaner</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://automaniacmrk.github.io/DryIceBlastingServices/dry-ice-blasting-services.html"/>
        <id>https://automaniacmrk.github.io/DryIceBlastingServices/dry-ice-blasting-services.html</id>

        <updated>2022-06-27T07:21:22-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Dry Ice Blasting Services Combustible Dust Cleaning Services We offer combustible vacuum cleaning services that allow us to deliver state-of-the art explosion-proof vacuums to our clients to remove volatile combustible particles, which is a growing concern for government agencies. The explosion-proof cleaning process is compliant&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h1>Dry Ice Blasting Services</h1>
<h2><img loading="lazy" src="https://midamericaservicesolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/MVIMG_20190121_195329-scaled-e1595959839770.jpg" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Dry Ice Blasting Services" width="80%" height="auto"></h2>
<h2>Combustible Dust Cleaning Services</h2>
<p>We offer combustible vacuum cleaning services that allow us to deliver state-of-the art explosion-proof vacuums to our clients to remove volatile combustible particles, which is a growing concern for government agencies. The explosion-proof cleaning process is compliant with all applicable standards and prevents our clients being subject to significant fines because of recent changes in laws governing combustible dust environment.</p>
<p>Advanced Environmental is trained in accordance to NFPA 654. NFPA 654 is the standard for the prevention of fire and dust explosions from the manufacturing, processing, and handling of combustible particulate solids and all other applicable regulatory requirements and standards.</p>
<h2>How Does Dry Ice Blasting Work?</h2>
<p>Dry ice blasting is a non-destructive cleaning process that uses solid carbon dioxide to dislodge residue while leaving the surface intact. Dry ice blasting is similar to pressure washing. It uses compressed air to propel media at high speed towards a surface. In this case, the media are carbon dioxide particles, which form solid pellets when cooled to -109.3 degrees Fahrenheit. Blasting frozen carbon dioxide onto a surface has three immediate effects:</p>
<ul>
<li>The surface's contents freeze and fracture due to thermal shock before the pellets even make contact.</li>
<li>The high-speed collision between the pellets and the brittle surface contaminants breaks unwanted residue into small pieces.</li>
<li>The dry ice quickly vaporizes when exposed to ambient air at room temperature. This results in more debris being released.</li>
</ul>
<h2><img loading="lazy" src="https://334646-1028689-raikfcquaxqncofqfm.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/CO2-Blasting-Blade-Attachment-Grooves-Turbine-Rotor.jpg" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Dry Ice Blasting Services" width="80%" height="auto"></h2>
<h2>Here are a few of the benefits to dry ice blasting:</h2>
<ul>
<li>Companies won't experience much downtime due to the fact that machines don't need disassembly or reassembly.</li>
<li>A quicker clean, that's non-abrasive, non-conductive, non-flammable.</li>
<li>There is no secondary waste or cleanup, which saves money on labor and expenses.</li>
<li>Our blasting nozzles allow us to get into tight spaces - this can be a problem for companies that use other cleaning methods.</li>
<li>Environment-friendly - Meets the requirements of USDA, FDA, and EPA.</li>
<li>Employees are safe - there is no need to expose them to chemicals and grit media</li>
</ul>
<p>* Please have your EHS manager contact us if you are in a flammable environment so we can procure a safe workplace*</p>
<h2>Our Technology</h2>
<p>Dry ice cleaning is non-abrasive, non-conductive, non-toxic, and non-flammable. It is also chemical free, water free and does not create secondary waste streams. The dry ice blasting machine is incredibly versatile and can be used for a wide range of applications and industries.</p>
<p>The benefits of dry ice blasting</p>
<ul>
<li>Increase efficiency Clean equipment online, while eliminating need for cooldown and disassembly.</li>
<li>Secondary waste is not produced by dry ice blasting.</li>
<li>Non-abrasive Dry Ice is a media that does not cause damage to substrates.</li>
<li>Higher quality parts and less scrap</li>
<li>Operator safe Eliminates need for chemicals and repetitive, manual processes.</li>
<li>Non-toxic and non-conductive Dry ice is a food grade media and is safe for commercial use.</li>
</ul>
<h2><img loading="lazy" src="https://hagerty-media-prod.imgix.net/2021/04/Dry-Ice-Lede.jpg?auto=format%2Ccompress&amp;fit=crop&amp;ixlib=php-3.3.0&amp;max-h=584&amp;max-w=640" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Dry Ice Blasting Services" width="80%" height="auto"></h2>
<h2>How to Use Abrasive Blazing</h2>
<ul>
<li>Abrasive blasting offers flexibility because of the variety of media available. You can choose the media that best suits the surface and remove the contaminants. When the surrounding surface is free from electrical and mechanical components, such as concrete silos, brick walls, or other steel structures, abrasive blasting can be used. This method is also used when the surface needs to be profiled for another application or shaping of the surface needs to happen. Abrasive blasting requires cleanup of media and will not work in indoor areas that can't handle dust and excess mess.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Because of the wide range of media options, abrasive blasting allows for flexibility. The media chosen can be customized to fit the surface material and the contaminant being removed.</li>
<li>When the surrounding surface is free from electrical and mechanical components that might be damaged by the media used (e.g. a brick wall or concrete silo), abrasive blasting can work well.</li>
<li>When the surface is to be profiled or shaped for another purpose, this method can also be used.</li>
<li>Abrasive blasting requires cleanup of media. If indoor space is not able to handle the mess, then abrasive blasting might not work.</li>
</ul>
<h2>More About Dry Ice Blasting</h2>
<p>The three ways in which dry ice blasting works on your surface cleaning project:</p>
<ul>
<li>Thermal effect cleaning action. As the dry ice strikes the substrate surface, the temperature of both the dirt/residue layer and the substrate decreases. The freezing cold ice hitting the surface lowers the temperatures of different materials in unequal ways, for instance food residue freezes faster than the stainless steel surface underneath, and this effect causes the food to shrink and releases surface adhesion or surface tension, allowing the impact to remove the debris. This thermal effect helps to separate the dirt/residue from the substrate.</li>
<li>Sublimation refers to the process where dry ice is converted almost immediately back into gas. The ice-to-gas conversion occurs when the solid ice hits the surface. This releases the entire energy used to make the gas solid. It also creates an explosive reaction that multiplies the cleaning force, trapping dirt and increasing its potency.</li>
</ul>
<h2><img loading="lazy" src="https://polarclean.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Mechanical-Dry-Ice-Blasting-Indianapolis-IN-5.1-After.jpg" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Dry Ice Blasting Services" width="80%" height="auto"></h2>
<h2>Information</h2>
<p>TuneRS Motorsports' award-winning CryoDetail(r) division is the first and original dry ice blasting facility in North America for automotive restoration and preservation. We have over a decade of experience with millions of dollars worth of exotic and rare vehicles. Experts, collectors and judges of concours are all familiar with CryoDetail(r). CryoDetail(r) is a pioneer in this field and we look forward to taking your car to the next level.</p>
<p>CryoDetail(r), which can restore any vehicle and its mechanical parts, such as engines, suspensions, transmissions, and more, will significantly reduce the labor required to clean them. This results in significant cost savings when it comes to vehicle restoration or preservation.</p>
<p>CryoDetail(r) offers the only environmentally friendly EPA approved method for industrial cleaning that can eliminate hundreds of hours of labor that was once needed to clean components. Our dry ice method does not require the use of any harmful chemicals and does not leave behind any residues. CryoDetail(r), is the most eco-friendly and safest method for conserving and/or maintaining your vehicle.</p>
<p>Some clients are happy to have their track and daily cars treated with CryoDetail(r), but clients who own antique and collector cars also find this service attractive to preserve or turn them into concours and show car winners. Some of the cars won Concours d'Elegance Awards at Pebble Beach and PCA National Parade as well as Cavallino Classic, Celebration Exotic Festivals, Mandarin By The Bay, Amelia Island, Cavallino Classic, Celebration Exotic Festival, Celebration Exotic Festival, Mandarin By The Bay, Mandarin By The Bay, Amelia Island, among others.</p>
<p>Thanks for visiting our site and do feel welcome to browse the cars in our portfolio as well as our video demonstrations. Also please do not hesitate to call us directly to bring your vehicle back to it's factory new look.</p>
<h2>What is Dry Ice used in Cleaning?</h2>
<p>Dry ice cleaning and blasting uses compressed air to force CO2 pellets out of a tube through a narrow tip aimed at the surface to be cleaned. It looks similar to sandblasting or pressure washing, but the main difference is dry ice. The CO2 is so cold - 109deg below zero - that it causes the dirt molecules to shrink, loosening them from the surface. As soon as the ice pellets hit the surface they change from solid to gas, creating a molecular "blast" that pries off dirt, grime and paint without significantly lowering the temperature of the surface.</p>
<ul>
<li>Only thing you need to do now is clean up any paint, glue, resins, asphalt or grime that has been left behind. There is no waste water. No chemical drainage. No sand or plastic beads scattered around. The CO2 solid pellets dissipate into the air and are absorbed by the atmosphere.</li>
<li>There is no dust or detritus from dry ice blasting that can be trapped in or foul up either the machinery being cleaned or nearby equipment.</li>
<li>They are safe for the workplace and do not pose a danger to equipment or people.</li>
</ul>
<p>Ice Cleaning eliminates the need to disassemble industrial equipment and move it to an area for cleaning. Then, it can be returned to its original location to be reassembled. This allows you to clean it in situ, which greatly reduces downtime. Dry ice blasting is very agile and can reach most areas. You can clean the entire thing by doing some in-place disassembly if necessary.</p>
<h2><img loading="lazy" src="https://cisp.cachefly.net/assets/articles/images/resized/0000985848_resized_dryiceblasting2.jpg" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Dry Ice Blasting Services" width="80%" height="auto"></h2>
<h2>Dry Ice Cleaning And Blasting In Industrial Applications</h2>
<p>Because you don’t need to wait for chemicals or water to dry, electrical parts and generators are immediately ready to go. Because radioactive residue is smaller than the waste water from pressure washing, dry ice blasting makes it easier to remove them. Applications around the globe are using dry ice for cleaning, including:</p>
<ul>
<li>Inside Heat Exchanger Tubes - Inside Diameter (ID)</li>
<li>Outside Fin Fans Cooler cleaning</li>
<li>Fire Restoration and Cleanup</li>
<li>Smoke Damage Restoration</li>
<li>Printing presses</li>
<li>Cleaning of manufacturing equipment</li>
<li>Piping Cleaning and Maintenance</li>
<li>Storage tanks</li>
<li>Reactor Cleaning</li>
<li>Shell and Tube Heating exchangers</li>
<li>Equipment for the oil field</li>
<li>Turbines, transformers</li>
<li>Sub-stations for power</li>
<li>Boilers</li>
<li>Molds and Presses</li>
<li>Electric Motors and Circuit Boards</li>
<li>Food Processing Equipment</li>
<li>Generators</li>
<li>Gears</li>
</ul>
<p>Industries and commercial companies are also using dry ice blasting to complete periodic maintenance cleaning projects, because of the ability to avoid or isolate downtime. This method is increasingly being employed in the food sector for the safe cleaning of packaging lines and ovens.</p>
<p>The replacement of solvents, which can cause damage to the environment or pose a danger in workplaces (e.g. acids and caustics), has been dry ice. This also eliminates the very expensive hazardous waste disposal costs to get rid of both the chemical drainage and the residue which has been contaminated by the chemicals.</p>
<h2>Benefits of Dry Ice Cleaning Services with Co2</h2>
<p>Dry ice blasting is a popular choice for industrial plants who are looking for effective equipment cleaning techniques.</p>
<p>Environmentally Friendly</p>
<p>The CO2 pellets penetrate the contaminant layer and upon impact, sublimate to a gas and thereby generate no secondary waste. The CO2 liquid used to generate the pellets is originally captured as a waste product and recycled, allowing EAI to create dry ice pellets.</p>
<p>Non-Destructive</p>
<p>The CO2 pellets are abrasive but will not damage the surface being cleaned.</p>
<p>Highly Effective</p>
<p>Because dry ice blasting has a unique expansion and flushing effect, it cleans more effectively because dried ice pellets shrink 700x when they are applied to the cleaning nozzle.</p>
<p>Flexible Availability</p>
<p>As a dry, efficient process, CO2 blasting is safe for a variety of industrial environments, including operations around electrical equipment.</p>
<h2><img loading="lazy" src="https://334646-1028689-raikfcquaxqncofqfm.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/CO2-Blasting-Blade-Attachment-Grooves-Turbine-Rotor.jpg" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Dry Ice Blasting Services" width="80%" height="auto"></h2>
<h2>Comparison of Dry Ice Blasting to Other Methods</h2>
<p>There are many available methods for cleaning industrial equipment. Each method has advantages and drawbacks, and some are comparable to dry ice blasting in some areas while falling short in others. This is how other cleaning methods stack up against dry ice blasting:</p>
<ul>
<li>Abrasive blasting. Unlike dry ice blasting, abrasive blasting is highly toxic and dangerous for the operator. To avoid being exposed to fumes or dust, the operator should wear a mask and a breathing device.</li>
<li>Soda blasting. Abrasive blasting can be used in a variety of ways, including soda blasting.</li>
<li>You can pressure wash. Pressure washing, like dry ice blasting is not abrasive. It does not cause any harm to the environment by emitting or toxic chemicals. This method, however, is not electrically conductive and requires wastewater disposal.</li>
<li>Tools for hand. Hand tools are environmentally safe, don't use toxic materials, require no special waste considerations, and are not electrically conductive. Hand tools have a lot of disadvantages, including abrasiveness and additional labor requirements.</li>
</ul>
<p>There are a variety of safety benefits included with dry ice blasting which might not be found using other industrial cleaning methods. The most prominent of these include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Elimination of toxic chemicals and emissions</li>
<li>Reduced waste of cleaning solutions</li>
<li>Surface degradation by abrasives prevented</li>
</ul>
<h2>Industries And Applications Of Dry Ice Blasting</h2>
<p>Dry ice blasting is an effective solution for removing unwanted contaminants and residues from the production process, such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>Oils</li>
<li>Adhesives</li>
<li>Resins</li>
<li>Paints</li>
<li>Greases</li>
<li>Asphalt tars</li>
<li>Biofilms</li>
<li>Aerospace. The aerospace sector relies on dry ice blasting to remove mastic from parts; clean turbine blades; remove labels from fuselage; and clean hydraulics, electrical components and circuitry, and landing gear.</li>
<li>Automotive. Dry ice blasting is ideal for cleaning engine blocks and components, undercarriages, wheels and axles, automotive production equipment, and more.</li>
<li>Power plants and electrical equipment. Dry ice blasting is often used to remove oil residue and/or corrosion from power generation equipment, such as turbines and generators. Dry ice blasting is also used in nuclear decontamination and for resin removal in the production of transformers.</li>
<li>Fire remediation. After a fire, dry ice blasting can be used to remove any charring or ash from other usable components.</li>
<li>Foundries and metal production. This process is used by foundries for cleaning molds and pressing equipment, stripping paint and rust, deburring and cleaning welder robots, residue removal and many other purposes.</li>
<li>Mold remediation. For applications that require sanitation, dry ice blasting offers an ideal solution for removing mold and mildew from substrates, walls, floors, and other surfaces.</li>
</ul>
<h2><img loading="lazy" src="https://cryodetail.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/cryodetail-banner-3.jpg" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Dry Ice Blasting Services" width="80%" height="auto"></h2>
<h2>The Project Required That The Walls Be Cleaned Down To White Metal</h2>
<p>Dry ice blasting can be used to remove heavy slag and clean sensitive semi-conductors. This is a fast and simple process that can be done quickly at a low cost.</p>
<ul>
<li>Fast: There is almost no post-cleanup because there is no waste water, unlike steam cleaning or chemicals</li>
<li>It is simple: the technique leaves no dust or grit behind, even though it is just as efficient as abrasive blasting.</li>
<li>It is cost-effective: Many machinery can be cleaned online or with little downtime. There are no disposal costs or time losses.</li>
</ul>
<p>Cleaning with dry ice protects any surface under the grime without abrasion. Unlike sand, bead blasting, or chemicals, dry ice (CO2) pellets will not leave pits or scratches. CO2 isn't a dangerous chemical unlike many industrial cleaning solvents.</p>
<h2>Environmentally Friendly</h2>
<p>The EPA actually recommends dry ice blasting as an alternative to many types of solvent-based cleaning since dry-ice blasting leaves no chemical residue. This is because the dry ice sublimates at room temperature.</p>
<p>Dry ice blasting is capable of cleaning many objects that have complex, diverse geometries. Dry ice blasting is useful for aerospace and semiconductor industries due to its ability to subliminate without leaving behind any residue.</p>
<p>Dry ice blasting is more efficient than other methods of blasting and produces less waste products. It also doesn't require the removal or cleaning up of blasting media. The waste products can be swept up, vacuumed or washed away depending on the containment.</p>
<h2><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.coldsweep.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Dry-Ice2-1024x680.jpg" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Dry Ice Blasting Services" width="80%" height="auto"></h2>
<h2>Food Processing Equipment Safety</h2>
<p>Advanced Environmental has a large number of food processing facilities that produce meat and frozen food. It was important that our cleaning product was food-grade certified by FDA, USDA, and EPA. Our CO2 blasting solutions are safe for food equipment cleaning.</p>
<h2>Dry Ice Blasting</h2>
<p>Our mission statement: We provide innovative industrial cleaning solutions to help customers become more efficient and environmentally-friendly.</p>
<h2><img loading="lazy" src="https://dryiceecogreen.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/dry1-blog-.jpg" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Dry Ice Blasting Services" width="80%" height="auto"></h2>
<h2>What is Abrasive Blasting?</h2>
<p>Abrasive blasting uses a pressurized vessel which forces blast media out of a hose at high velocity. You can use media such as silicon carbide and sodium bicarbonate or crushed glass to remove coatings.</p>
<h2>Industries Served</h2>
<p>Advanced Environmental offers expert cleaning and restoration services for many industries, including aviation, automobile, electric motors, generators, food, beverage, foundries and medical device manufacturing. We also offer packaging and printing, power-generation plants, plastics, printing machines, real estate, and other important areas.</p>
<h2><img loading="lazy" src="https://polarclean.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Food-Dry-Ice-Blasting-Ohio-Pic-2.jpg" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Dry Ice Blasting Services" width="80%" height="auto"></h2>
<h2>Dry Ice Cleaning Applications Across Industries</h2>
<p>Businesses across many industries can use ice blasting as a cleaning method. Dry ice cleaning is used in many commercial settings, including:</p>
<h2>Do You Wish You Had A Cleaning Option That Was Non-Toxic, Non-Abrasive, Non-Flammable, And That Strips Away Dirt, Grime, Oil And Dust Fast, Effectively, And Without Adding Additional Waste?</h2>
<p>Advanced Environmental offers the best dry ice blasting solution in Columbus, and our dry ice blasting process can clean your industrial space, warehouse, and equipment quickly at an affordable rate!</p>
<h2><img loading="lazy" src="http://powercleanindustrial.com/media/uploads/0/125_file-3.jpeg" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Dry Ice Blasting Services" width="80%" height="auto"></h2>
<h2>Dry Ice Industrial Cleaning Case Study Fin Fan Cooler: Before and After Heat Exchanger Cleaning</h2>
<p>Examples of before (left image) and after (right image) of Clean-Co Systems Dry Ice Blasting inside fin fan tubes.</p>
<h2>When To Use Dry Ice Blasting</h2>
<ul>
<li>Dry ice blasting is ideal for delicate surfaces or cleaning electrical and mechanical equipment. Dry ice is easy to clean as it disintegrates on contact.</li>
<li>Dry ice blasting does not create a profile on a surface. This makes it great for historical restoration projects.</li>
<li>Dry ice cleaning is safe for the environment as well as the workers. Not only are chemicals not used, but no harmful by-products are produced through the cleaning process.</li>
</ul>
<h2><img loading="lazy" src="https://cryodetail.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/cryodetail-banner-3.jpg" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Dry Ice Blasting Services" width="80%" height="auto"></h2>
<h2>Dry Ice Cleaning &amp; Blasting Services</h2>
<p>When you need cleaning processes that are safe and effective, consider dry ice blasting services. Dry ice cleaning is powerful and effective. It can remove stubborn residue and grime without using harsh chemicals.</p>
<p>At Environmental Alternatives, Inc. (EAI), we enhance the quality of our dry ice blasting services by making our own dry ice on demand at our work site. On-site dry ice production allows for greater efficiency, so you can get the comprehensive cleaning services you need for your industrial environment.</p>
<h2>Moisture Sensitive Solution</h2>
<p>Dry ice blasting is a cleaning process that completely skips liquid phases. This means your electronics will be protected from moisture. The dry ice instantly transforms from solid into gas, so that there's no corrosion or damage to your electrical components.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
